Hui Ye

18 Tat Chee Avenue, Kowloon, Hong Kong 852-65769246

huiyehy@outlook.com https://huiye19.github.io

RESEARCH INTEREST

My research interests lie in the intersection of **Human-Computer Interaction (HCI)** and **Computer Graphics (CG)**. Specifically, my main research focus is on exploring novel mobile AR prototyping and programming tools and techniques for 3D contents and interactions.

EDUCATION

09/2017 - City University of Hong Kong (CityU)

08/2022 Ph.D. in Creative Media

Thesis: 3D Content and Interaction Prototyping with Mobile Augmented Reality

Supervisor: Prof. Hongbo Fu

Committee: Hongbo Fu, Kening Zhu, Weiyin Ma, Karan Singh

09/2012 - University of Science and Technology of China (USTC)

06/2016 B.A. in Communication (Honorary Rank, Top 5%)

Minor in Computer Science and Technology

EXPERIENCE

09/2022 - City University of Hong Kong

Current RGC Postdoctoral Fellow

Supervisor: Prof. Hongbo Fu

09/2021 - City University of Hong Kong

08/2022 Research Assistant

Supervisor: Prof. Hongbo Fu

12/2019 - Tsinghua University

04/2020 Institute of HCI and Media Integration

Visiting Ph.D. Student

PULICATIONS

- P1 **Hui Ye**, Jiaye Leng (joint first author), Pengfei Xu, Karan Singh, and Hongbo Fu. ProInterAR: A Visual Programming Platform for Creating Immersive AR Interactions. *In Proceedings of the 2024 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems*. ACM, 2024. **(CHI 2024)**
- P2 **Hui Ye**, Jiaye Leng, Chufeng Xiao, Lili Wang, and Hongbo Fu. ProObjAR: Prototyping Spatially-aware Interactions of Smart Objects with AR-HMD. *In Proceedings of the 2023 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems*. ACM, 2023. **(CHI 2023)**
- P3 **Hui Ye** and Hongbo Fu. ProGesAR: Mobile AR Prototyping for Proxemic and Gestural Interactions with Real-world IoT Enhanced Spaces. *In Proceedings of the 2022 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems*. ACM, 2022. **(CHI 2022)**
- P4 **Hui Ye**, Kin Chung Kwan (joint first author), Wanchao Su, and Hongbo Fu. ARAnimator: In-situ Character Animation in Mobile AR with User-defined Motion Gestures. *ACM Transactions on Graphics (TOG): Special Issue for ACM SIGGRAPH 2020*. ACM, 2020. **(SIGGRAPH 2020)**
- P5 **Hui Ye**, Kin Chung Kwan, and Hongbo Fu. 3D Curve Creation on and around Physical Objects with Mobile AR. *IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics*. IEEE, 2021. **(TVCG)**

- P6 Wanchao Su, **Hui Ye**, Shuyu Chen, Lin Gao, and Hongbo Fu. DrawingInStyles: Portrait Image Generation and Editing with Spatially Conditioned StyleGAN. *IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics*. IEEE, 2022. **(TVCG)**
- P7 Xuanyu Wang, **Hui Ye**, Christian Sandor, Weizhan Zhang, and Hongbo Fu. Predict-and-Drive: Avatar Motion Adaption in Room-Scale Augmented Reality Telepresence with Heterogeneous Spaces. *IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics: Special Issue for IEEE ISMAR 2022.* **IEEE**, 2022. **(TVCG)**
- P8 Yanxiang Zhang and **Hui Ye**. Time-Based Nonlinear Interactive Player. *In Augmented Reality, Virtual Reality, and Computer Graphics: Third International Conference, AVR* 2016. Springer, 2016.
- P9 Yanxiang Zhang, Yun Zhu, and **Hui Ye**. 2015. The Design of an Augmented Reality Based Rigid Body Motion Experiment System. *Applied Mechanics and Materials*. Trans Tech Publications Ltd, 2015.

PATENTS

- PT1 Hongbo Fu, **Hui Ye**, and Chufeng Xiao. Prototyping Applications Of Spatially Aware Smart Objects Using Augmented Reality. U.S. Patent 18/335,559, 2023.
- PT2 Hongbo Fu and **Hui Ye**. Mobile AR Prototyping for Proxemic and Gestural Interactions with Real-world IoT Enhanced Spaces. U.S. Patent 17/810,714, 2022.

SELECTED HONORS & AWARDS

2023	Science and Technology Progress Award of Anhui (Third Prize)
2022	RGC Postdoctoral Fellowship
2022	Outstanding Academic Performance Award of CityU
2021	Shidi CAD&CG Excellent Student Award
2020	Research Tuition Scholarship of CityU
2016	Guo Moruo Scholarship (Top 1.7%, Highest Honor for USTC Undergraduates)
2016	Merit Graduate of Anhui Province & USTC (Top 3%)
2016	Outstanding Thesis of USTC
2014	Sun Bin Leadership Scholarship of USTC
2014	Aegon-Industrial Responsibility Scholarship of USTC
2013-15	Outstanding Instructor in "Science and Technology Week" of USTC
2013	Gold Award of Excellent Student Scholarship of USTC (Top 5%)
2013	Outstanding Young Volunteer of USTC

TALKS

05/2023	ProObjAR: Prototyping Spatially-aware Interactions of Smart Objects with AR-HMD Conference Paper Presenter, CHI 2023
08/2022	From Communication to Computer Graphics Invited Presenter, Student Colloquium, CAD&CG 2022+2023
05/2022	ProGesAR: Mobile AR Prototyping for Proxemic and Gestural Interactions with Real-world IoT Enhanced Spaces Conference Paper Presenter, CHI 2022
04/2022	Mobile AR Prototyping for Proxemic and Gestural Interactions Invited Speaker, EAA Youth Academic Forum, Tianjin Fine Arts Institute

12/2021 Exploring Novel Mobile AR Prototyping Techniques and Tools for 3D Contents

SIGGRAPH Thesis Fast Forward 2021

2020-21 ARAnimator: In-situ Character Animation in Mobile AR with User-defined Motion Gestures

Invited Speaker, Graphics And Mixed Environment Symposium (GAMES), 09/2021 Invited Speaker, SCM|ACIM Colloquium, CityU, 10/2020

Conference Paper Presenter, SIGGRAPH 2020, 08/2020

03/2021 3D Curve Creation on and around Physical Objects with Mobile AR

Invited Speaker, IEEE VR 2021

03/2021 In-situ 3D Content Creation in Mobile AR

Invited Speaker, Affiliated Forum on Human, Technology and Future of IWHEC 2021

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

- 2018-19 Teaching Assistant, SM1103A Introduction to Media Computing, CityU
 - 2018 Teaching Assistant, SM2716 Physical Computing & Tangible Media, CityU

PROFESSIONAL SERVICE

Program Committees

- 2023-24 ACM Conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work and Social Computing (CSCW)
 - 2024 ACM Special Interest Group on Computer Graphics (SIGGRAPH Asia) Emerging Technologies
 - 2024 ACM International Joint Conference on Pervasive and Ubiquitous Computing (UbiComp/ISWC) Notes and Briefs
- 2023-24 ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI) Late-Breaking Work
 - 2022 ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI) Student Research Competition

Conference Review

- 2024 ACM Special Interest Group on Computer Graphics (SIGGRAPH)
- 2022-23 ACM Special Interest Group on Computer Graphics (SIGGRAPH Asia)
- 2020-24 ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI): Special Recognitions for Outstanding Reviews
- 2023-24 ACM Conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work and Social Computing (CSCW): Special Recognitions for Outstanding Reviews
- 2020/23 Pacific Conference on Computer Graphics and Applications (PG)
 - 2022 ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology (UIST)
 - ACM International Conference on Mobile Human-Computer Interaction (MobileHCI): Special Recognitions for Outstanding Reviews
 - 2021 IEEE Virtual Reality (VR)
 - 2021 IEEE International Conference on Artificial Intelligence and Virtual Reality (AIVR)

Journal Review

- 2024 ACM Transactions on Graphics (TOG)
- 2024 IEEE Transactions on Mobile Computing (TMC)
- 2023 Computers & Graphics (C&G)
- 2023 IEEE Computer Graphics and Applications (CG&A)
- 2023 The Visual Computer (TVC)
- 2022 IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics (TVCG)

Student Helper

2018 Pacific Conference on Computer Graphics and Applications (PG)

Last updated on April 5, 2024